Guide to the Leigh N. Ortenburger Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 15: Photography
  - Subseries 15.2: Early photos of Tetons, all mounted, mounted size 10x13"
    - Climber (possibly Buckingham, William J.), climber (possibly Buckingham, William J.), climber rappelling (possibly Ortenburger, Leigh N.) (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - North Face of Grand Teton, Middle Teton from northeast, Middle Teton from southeast (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Mount Owen, peak (unidentified), Symmetry Spire, Ice and Storm Points, Grand Teton and Mount Owen from farther north with climber (unidentified) (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Peak and climber (both unidentified), Buck Mountain and Wister, the range (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Mount Moran from south, Teewinot, Nez Perce (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Ridge from Rockchuck to St. John and beyond, Mount Owen, Cloudveil Dome to South Teton with Buck Mountain in distance (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Red Sentinel from east, peak (unidentified), peak (unidentified) (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Peak (unidentified, possibly Middle Teton from south), North Face of Grand Teton, Grand Teton from southeast (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Climber (unidentified), snow scene, snow scene, two climbers (possibly on the "V" on Exum Ridge) (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Climber (unidentified) on Grand Teton, Grand Teton from Jackson Lake, two climbers (unidentified) (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Lake Solitude, group (possibly guided) approaching Lower Saddle, Jenny Lake and the Cathedral Group, a climber (unidentified) (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Grand Teton and Mount Owen from Cascade Canyon (2), climber (unidentified, possibly on Hangover Pinnacle) (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Two climbers (unidentified) climbing Hangover Pinnacle, climber (possibly Ortenburger, Leigh N.) rappelling, peak (unidentified) (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Teepe Pillar, climber (unidentified) rappelling, Grand Teton and Mount Owen from Cascade Canyon (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Grand Teton and Mount Owen from North Cascade (2), one with climber (unidentified), Cathedral Group from Jenny Lake (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Two climbers (unidentified) on steep pitch, peak (unidentified) two climbers (unidentified) on pinnacle (unidentified) (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Climber (unidentified) on summit of Mount Moran, ridge from Storm Point to Mount Woodring, Symmetry Spire (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Unknown view, Lev, Peter rappelling on Mount Owen with North Face of Grand in background, climber rappelling from Lower Saddle (unidentified, possibly Brewer, Richard) (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Climber (unidentified) rappelling, two climbers (unidentified, upper one possibly Exum, Glenn), climbing party on Wall Street (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Grand Teton summit photo (possibly Stanford Alpine Club), waterfall, the Range from Snake River overlook (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Grand Teton and Mount Owen, Pownall, Richard, two climbers (unidentified, upper one possibly Pownall, Richard) (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 15.3: Unmounted prints of Tetons, size 10.5x13.5"
    - Climber (possibly Brewer, Richard) rappelling from the Lower Saddle (12) (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Exum, Glenn (12), Irvin, Richard K., Mowat, John, and Clinch, Nicholas (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Jackson Hole through a chimney (4) (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - North Face of Grand Teton (4) (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Middle Teton from the north (11) (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Wall Street on the Exum Ridge of Grand Teton (13) (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Pownall, Richard, Unsoeld, Willi, Ortenburger, Leigh N. (2), two climbers (unidentified) rappelling (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Hangover Pinnacle with two climbers (unidentified), peak (unidentified), Grand Teton from far north, peak (unidentified), peak (unidentified), canyon (possibly South Fork of Cascade) (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Two climbers (unidentified) rappelling shot (2), Grand Teton from northwest, Grand from south, climber (unidentified) from summit of Mount Moran, climber (unidentified), climber (unidentified) (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Disappointment Peak with Delta, Bradley, and Taggart lakes, Cathedral Group, peak (unidentified), three climbers on snow (unidentified), peaks with snow (3) (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Middle Teton, Middle Teton Glacier, Grand Teton, Teewinot on right, Teewinot, peak (unidentified) (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Nez Perce, two climbers (unidentified) possibly on East Ridge of Grand Teton, climber (unidentified) rappelling, climber (unidentified) and peak, Middle Teton from northeast with climber (unidentified, possibly Ortenburger, Leigh N.), Mount Moran from south, Middle Teton from northeast (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - The "V" pitch on the Exum Ridge with three climbers (unidentified), the black dike on Moran (3), climber (unidentified) rappelling, Teewinot (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Cliff (unidentified), cliff (unidentified), cliff (unidentified, possibly corner of Wall Street), cliff (unidentified), panorama of the Teton Range from the valley (2 photos) (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Grand Teton from south,, Middle Teton Glacier with climber (unidentified) (2), pinnacle with climber (unidentified) (2), two climbers (unidentified) possibly showing top of East Ridge Snowfield and summit block of Grand Teton (2) (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Grand from west (2), climber (unidentified) on Wall Street, Mount Owen from northeast, East Ridge of Grand Teton, Storm Point from southwest, panoramic view (unidentified), Storm Point from southwest with route markings (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Mount Moran, clouds over head of Cascade Canyon, the Sierras (unidentified, possibly Palisades) (3) (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - El Capitan, the Three Brothers, climber (unidentified) on overhanging rappel (2) (all Yosemite), range (unidentified), peak and lake (unidentified, possibly the Sierras) (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Trial drawings of Grand Teton by Pownall, Quita, and Sauers (first name unknown) (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 15.4: Mounted prints of Tetons, size 10"x13"
    - Climbers (unidentified) on Grand Teton (mounted size 10x13") (2), portrait of four guides (Ortenburger, Leigh N. on left) (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Two climbers (unidentified), rappelling from Lower Saddle, Ortenburger, Leigh N., coiling a rope (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Three climbers (unidentified), party on snow, close-up of two climbers (unidentified) (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 15.5: Unmounted aerial photos and survey photos of Tetons
    - Phelps Lake aerial survey photo, copy (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Eight aerial survey photos of Teton Range from south to north, identified (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Four aerial photos of Teton Range, possibly by Austin Post, 9/23/1960 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Ten aerial photos of Teton Range by Austin Post, 9/6/1964 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Sixteen aerial photos of Teton Range, possibly by Austin Post, 8/19/1963 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Aerial survey photos, copies (Box 57, Folder 10-20)
  - Subseries 15.6: Photographic prints from the Cordillera Blanca, Peru, taken by Ortenburger, Leigh N., unless otherwise noted
    - List of negative numbers and mounted prints taken in 1952 in the Cordillera Blanca of Peru (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Three mounted 11x14" color prints of Chacraraju (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Mounted 11x14" prints, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 3-13)
    - List of negative numbers and mounted prints taken in 1954 in the Cordillera Blanca of Peru (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Mounted 11x14" prints, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 2-10)
    - Mounted 11x14" prints, 1954 (Box 60, Folder 1-10)
    - Christmas card original text (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Mounted Pisco panorama trials, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
    - Unmounted Pisco panorama trials, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
    - Unmounted prints, 1952 or 1954 (Box 61, Folder 1-13)
    - Mounted size 16x20" print, 1958, mounted 8.5x20" panorama, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Mounted size 14x18" prints, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 2-6)
    - Mounted size 14x18" prints, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 7-13)
    - Mounted size 16x20" prints, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
    - Mounted size 16x20" prints, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 7-14)
    - Miscellaneous unmounted prints sizes 8x10", print size 9x12" (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
    - Pisco panorama, unmounted, 14x17" (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Mounted color print, size 14x18" (location of peak unidentified) (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Unmounted 16x20" prints (unidentified) (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Unmounted 14x17" prints (unidentified) (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Chacraraju 14x17" prints (3) (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Panorama from summit of Huascarán, 14x17" prints, (3 photos) (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Unmounted 14x17" prints (3), print of Everest Group taken from Makalu, Nepal 1961 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Photo captions for American Andean Expedition 1954, for various sizes of slides and 8x10" prints (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Photo captions submitted to National Geographic, 1962, for 35 mm slides by Beardsley, Irene, 8x10" prints, and 4x5 color transparencies (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous photo captions (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", 1952, identified on back (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", 1954, identified on back, one by Bell, George I. (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", 1958, some identified on back (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", 1959, some identified on back (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Unmounted prints, Makalu, Nepal, miscellaneous sizes, including three-part panorama, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", South Peak of Huandoy 1964 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", Chacraraju 1964 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", with captions, 1971 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", identified but no date (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", identified but no date (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Unmounted prints, 8x10", unidentified, no date (Box 66, Folder 2-6)
    - Christmas cards with photos from Peru, one from Grand Teton National Park, Wyoming (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 15.7: Negatives of the Tetons taken by Ortenburger, Leigh, sizes 2¼"x3¼" or 4x5, black and white unless noted
    - Misplaced negatives and contact prints (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Red Sentinel, Hangover Pinnacle, Ice Point, old pitons left in camp on first ascent of Grand Teton in 1898 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh self portrait in 1948, children, Cathedral Peak in the Sierras, some with contact prints (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Owen Chimney, Pittman aerials, winter attempt on Grand Teton, some with contact prints (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - The Enclosure on the Grand Teton, scenic shots (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N. (3), scenic shots, with contact prints (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Ortenburger, Leigh N. and crevasse, Pownall, Richard, Guide's Hill and old cabin, with contact prints (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - North Face of Grand Teton, 1953, more climbing shots on Grand Teton, the "V" pitch (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Exum, Glenn, guiding, more climbing shots on Grand, some with contacts (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Rappel from Lower Saddle, helicopter flight (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Aerials of Teton Range, 1956-1957, 1989 helicopter flight (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - More aerials of Teton Range, some with contact prints (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - More aerials, scenic shots, 1957, 1988 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Table Mountain trip, no contact prints (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Color transparencies including climbing on Grand Teton, Hangover Pinnacle, scenic views (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Sierras, Palisades, with contact prints (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Photos of maps of Tetons, copies of articles by Horberg, Leland, Edmund, R. W., and Fryxell, Fritiof M.; Iddings, Joseph Paxson, and Weed, Walter Harvey (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 15.8: Negatives of the Cordillera Blanca, Peru, taken by Ortenburger, Leigh N., size 4"x5" and black and white unless otherwise noted, if numbered see index to negatives and enlargements, card indicates enlargement details, 1952-1961
    - Negatives and contacts, (not numbered, not enlarged), 1952 (Box 68, Folder 710)
    - Index to 1952-1954 numbered negatives and enlargements (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 2-4)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 5-7)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Negatives, not numbered, year unknown (empty) (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 3-4)
    - Negatives and contact prints, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 5-6)
    - Negatives, no contact prints, 195870.8 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Negatives and contact prints, 1958 (Box 71, Folder 1-4)
    - Peru, Macchu Picchu, negatives and contact prints, 1958 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, 1959 (Box 71, Folder 6-7)
    - Negatives and contact prints, numbered, Alpamayo, 1959 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Negatives and contact prints, no numbers, probably 1959 or 1964 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Negatives and contact prints, Eliseo Vargas and family, no date (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Karakorum, negatives and contact prints of maps and manuscripts (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Negatives and contact prints, 2¼"x3¼", not numbered, 1959 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Negatives and contact prints, 2¼"x3¼", numbered and identified, taken by Ganci, Joseph David (Dave), 1959 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Negatives and contact prints, three panoramas, 1959 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Nepal, Makalu Expedition, negatives and contact prints, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 4-8)
    - Nepal, Makalu Expedition, negatives, no contact prints, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Nepal, Makalu Expedition, color transparencies, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Nepal or Peru, color transparencies and internegatives (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 15.9: Negatives and color transparencies of North American parks, of ruins on a trip around the world in 1961, and at Leigh's father's memorial service, size 4x5", taken by Ortenburger, Leigh N., 1950s-1962
    - Color transparencies of National Parks (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
    - Negatives and contact prints of Yosemite (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Lost Arrow, Yosemite, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Mt. Gayley, Sierras, early winter (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Mt. Williamson, Sierras (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Sierras from White Mountain (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Canada, 1956 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Canada, Columbia Icefield, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Trip around world, Hawaii, Angkor Wat, Taj Mahal, Persepolis, Luxor, Petra, Athens, Crete, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 10-16)
    - Memorial Service for Ortenburger, Arthur I., (father), Galiano Island, BC, Canada, January 1962 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 15.10: Negatives of the Cordillera Blanca, Peru, taken by Ortenburger, Leigh, size 4x5" and black and white unless otherwise noted, 1964-1985
    - Negatives and contact prints, Palcaraju, South Peak of Huandoy, Chacraraju, 1964 (Box 74, Folder 1-8)
    - Color internegatives, 1964 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Negatives, some contact prints and printing cards, 1971 (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
    - Negatives and contact prints, Rinrihirca, Pucahirca Central, Huascarán Norte, Huascarán Sur, Ranrapalca, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Negatives, no contact prints, 1981 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Color transparencies, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Negatives, no contact prints, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Negatives, no contact prints, photographic expedition, 1985 (Box 75, Folder 8-9)
    - Color transparencies, years unknown (Box 75, Folder 10)